approved Pythagoras Theorem really
quickly I've drawn a square here with
another Square inside it and this gives
me four congruent right angled triangles
which have these side lengths A and B
all equal to each other if we calculate
the area of the large Square we can do
that in two different ways I can just
think of it as a large square that has
side length a plus b so its area is a
plus b squared and if you multiply out a
plus b squared you get a squared plus b
squared plus 2 a b or I can think of it
as these four congruent right angle
triangles their areas are half base
times height so a half a times B so I
get a half a times B times four because
there are four of them and then I also
need to include this Square in the
middle which is a square of side length
C so it has area c squared so four times
a half is two that's two a B plus c
squared but these two expressions
represent the same area so they must be
equal to one another but they both
contain two a b so I can subtract that
from both sides of the equation so that
leaves us with Pythagoras theorem in the
familiar form a squared plus b squared
equals c squared and so that's how